Preliminary Inventory to the Faces of the enemy: video tape, 1987
Hoover Institution Archives
Faces of the enemy: video tape,
1987
94056
10 manuscript boxes (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Finished videotape copy, transcript, and raw videotape footage, relating to psychological dimensions of war, interstate rivalry, and social conflict. Produced by Quest Productions.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Hostility (Psychology); War--Psychological aspects.; Propaganda.; Peace.; Video tapes.; Quest Productions.
Container List
- FOTE conference, 1983 January (all FOTE conference tapes are 3/4" unless otherwise noted) (Box 1.)
  - 1 Sam Keen
  - 1A Sam Keen
  - 2 Ashley Montague
  - 2A Ashley Montague
  - 3 Ashley Montague
  - 3A Ashley Montague, Valentine Berzhkov
  - 4 Ashley Montague, Valentine Berzhkov (Box 2.)
  - 4A Valentine Berzhkov, Arthur Cox
  - 5 Valentine Berzhkov
  - 5A Discussion: Valentine Berzhkov, Sam Keen, Arthur Cox
  - 6 Discussion: Valentine Berzhkov, Sam Keen, Arthur Cox
  - 7 Discussion: Valentine Berzhkov, Sam Keen, Arthur Cox
  - 7A Robert Bly (Box 3.)
  - 7B Susan Griffin
  - 8A Robert Bly
  - 6A Susan Griffin, Richard Baker, Roshi (from 2nd part of 8A)
  - 8B Susan Griffin, Robert Bly
  - 9A Rev. William Sloane, Coffin, full discussion with Montague, Griffin, Coffin, Keen, Roshi, Bly
  - 9B Robert Bly (Box 4.)
  - 10A Full discussion with Montague, Griffin, Coffin, Keen, Roshi, Bly
  - 10B Robert Bly
  - 10C Robert Bly, Richard Baker, Roshi
  - 11B Rev. William Sloane, Coffin, panel discussion
  - 12B Panel discussion
  - 13B Panel discussion (Box 5.)
  - 14 Panel discussion, Bly "Fairytale"
- Posner tape 1
- Posner tape 2
- Posner tape 3
- FOTE conference, 1983 January
  - 4A (VHS DUB) Arthur Cox (plus Valentine Berzhkov, Sam Keen, and Arthur Cox in discussion)
  - 5 (VHS DUB) Valentine Berzhkov (Box 6.)
  - 11A (VHS DUB) Full discussion
  - 7A (VHS DUB) Robert Bly
  - 7B (VSH DUB) Robert Bly, Susan Griffin
  - 9B (VHS DUB) Robert Bly
  - 10B (VHS DUB) Robert Bly
- Miscelleneous unnumbered tapes
  - Seminar tape 1, 1985 November 11
  - Sam Keen in the USSR (young people in disco, slide show/discussion, young people)
  - Sam Keen in the USSR (young people in disco)
  - Morning, USSR, 1983 (Box 7.)
  - FOTE dub, 1984 November 13
  - Packaging American Wars (VHS) (WBRA TV)
- Miscelleneous numbered tapes collecetd during research for FACES OF THE ENEMY, 1987
  - 3 "The Bear"-1984 presidential reelection campaign commercial
  - 30 Mikhail Gorbachev and Alexander Haig on Nightline, 1985 October 1
  - 35 Ronald Reagan speech on Contras, 1986 March 16, and democratic reply by Senator Jim Sasser (TN). Includes 2 VHS DUBS (Box 8.)
  - 38 Ronald Reagan press conference, 1986 April 6. Includes VHS DUB
  - 44(VHS) Soldiers in hiding (HBO)
  - 122(VHS) Richard Nixon speech to World Affairs Council, 1986 (Box 9.)
  - 141 Propaganda selections III: Selections from old anti-communist propaganda films from Pierce Raffery
- VHS DUBS of filmed interviews for Faces of the Enemy (dubbed from the screen of the 16mm editing machine; the quality is therefore very rough)
  - E-7 Robert Lifton
  - E-8 Political cartoonists
  - E-10 Frederick(?) Hartman
  - E-22 Caspar Weinberger press conference, luncheon speech, St. Francis Hotel, San Francisco, with protesters outside)
  - E-23 Robert Ivey
- Finished videotape copy (Box 10.)
- Transcript